Finding Aid for the Alice Wolfskill Weyse Correspondence LSC.0112
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alice Wolfskill Weyse correspondence
1859-1943
1859-1897
UCLA Library Special Collections
Weyse, Alice Wolfskill
LSC.0112
1.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Alice Wolfskill (Barrows) Weyse was the granddaughter of William Wolfskill, a Southern California pioneer, and the daughter of Juanita Wolfskill Barrows and Henry D. Barrows. Henry Dwight Barrows arrived in Los Angeles, California in 1854. He was a teacher, County School Superintendent, U.S. Marshal (1861) and businessman. The collection consists primarily of letters from relatives and friends to Alice W.B. Weyse.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Brainerd Dyer, 1946.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942339883606533
Biography
Weyse was the granddaughter of William Wolfskill, Southern California pioneer; she was the daughter of Juanita Wolfskill Barrows and Henry D. Barrows; married to Henry Guenther Weyse.
Henry Dwight Barrows arrived in Los Angeles, California, 1854; taught in Southern California three years; married Juanita Wolfskill, November 14, 1860; served as County School Superintendent; appointed U.S. Marshal by President Lincoln (1861) and served four years; formed a partnership with J.D. Hicks, 1864, selling tin and hardware; manufactured pipe, ca. 1874; lived with his daughter Alice for several years contributing to the Historical Society and continuing his strong interest in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
Collection consists primarily of letters from relatives and friends to Alice W.B. Weyse. The collection also includes correspondence of Henry D. Barrows, related ephemera of the family of Alice W.B. Weyse, and a report titled The correspondence and letters of Henry Dwight Barrow (1879-1897), written by Elsa Fichtuer, May 10, 1943. H.D. Barrows' letters provide accounts of early Southern California life.
Expanded Scope and Content
Letters from Henry Dwight Barrows to his daughters, Alice Wolfskill Barrows (Mrs. Henry Guenther Weyse) and Ada F. Barrows (Mrs. Rudolf Weyse), and from Alice and Ada Barrows to their parents. Also correspondence from Henry Guenther Weyse to Alice, his wife, from various friends to Alice, and miscellaneous correspondence of Henry G. Weyse. The collection also contains bills, checks, menus, photographs, etc. 1879-1897. (Material found in Santa Monica by Lieutenant D.D. Rasco and presented to the Library by Professor Brainerd Dyer, January 1946.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence of Alice Wolfskill (Barrows) Weyse, arranged by correspondents and dates (Box 1).
Misc. correspondence, papers (Box 2).
Letters (Correspondence).; Pioneers -- California -- Correspondence.; Barrows, Henry D.--Correspondence.; Weyse, Alice Wolfskill--Correspondence.; Barrows, Henry D.
- Correspondence: Alice Wolfskill (Barrows) Weyse
  - Notebook: a report on the correspondence and letters of Henry Dwight Barrows by Elizabeth Elsa Fichtner, May 10, 1943. (Box 1)
  - Letters from H.D. Barrows to his daughter Alice Wolfskill (Barrows) Weyse, 1879-1897. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to parents, Mr. & Mrs. H.D. Barrows, 1886-89. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Ada F. Barrows to parents, Mr. & Mrs. H.D. Barrows, 1886. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters to husband, Henry Guenther Weyse, 1889-1896. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Henry Guenther Weyse, 1889-1897. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters from sister Ada F. Barrows, 1887-1897. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters to sister Ada F. Barrows, 1888. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Augusta App, 1895-1897. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from John M. Carson, 1884. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Franklin S. Hovey, uncle, 1885-1886. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from Carrie Müller, 1886. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Ella M. Pinkham, Mills Seminary, 1879-1888. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence to Alice W. Barrows Weyse. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, Papers and Photographs
  - Personal and miscellaneous correspondence of Henry G. Weyse. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous letters, telegrams, etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous business papers, etc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets, views, menus, etc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Personal photographs. (Box 2, Folder 5)